Guide to the School of Art and Architecture, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records of the dean of the School of Art and Architecture, 1943-1976; Accession 2002-A-099
  - Dean Howard Weaver (1967-1970)
    - Subject Files
      - Report to President on Role of Arts in Undergraduate Education at Yale, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - S, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - St. Mary's College, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Save the Park, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Secretary's Office, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - Selective Service, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 24-25)
      - Silvermine College, 1966-1969 (Box 20, Folder 26-27)
      - Space Allocation, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 28)
      - Sterling Library, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 29)
      - Student Art Gallery, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 30)
      - Student Committee, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 31)
      - Summer, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 32)
      - Symbiosis: A Project for Yale, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 33)
      - T, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 34)
      - Television Studio, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 35)
      - Travel, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 36)
      - Treasurer's Office, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 37-38)
      - U, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 1)
      - University - general information, announcements, etc., 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 2)
      - University Council, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 3-4)
      - University Police, 1967-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 5)
      - Urban Studies, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 6)
      - V, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 7)
      - W, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 8)
      - Weaver, Howard J.
        - Invitations to, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 9)
        - News release, 1968 (Box 20A, Folder 10)
        - Notes, miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 11)
        - Personal Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 12)
      - Whiting Project, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 13)
      - Yale In China, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 14)
      - Yale Parking Authority, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 15)
      - Yale Reports, 1967-p1969 (Box 20A, Folder 16-17)
      - Yale Seminar in Modern Journalism, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 18)
      - Yale University Press
        - Committee on Printing and Design, 1967-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 19-20)
        - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 21)
        - Correspondence with the director, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 22)
        - Printing office, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 23)
      - X, Y, Z, 1968-1969 (Box 20A, Folder 24)
  - National Architectural Accrediting Board (NAAB) Reports
    - Evaluation Report
      - Academic year 1956-1957 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Academic year 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Academic year 1963-1964 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Program report
      - 1987 June (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - 1997 June (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
      - Appendices, 1997 June (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
  - Budgets, 1943-1968
    - Administration Budgets, 1943-1950 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 10-11)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Budget information, 1988-1992 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Business Managers Accounts, 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Division of Arts Meetings
    - Minutes, 1947 September-1950 May (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Annual Reports, 1942-1965
    - 1942-1947 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - 1947-1950 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - 1953 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - 1954 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 22, Folder 19)
      Includes information on new building dedication.
    - 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - 1988-1990 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Advisory Committee on Divisions of Arts
    - 1946-1947 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Memorial Tablet & Signs for New Building, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - University Architecture Policy (Saarinen signature), 1956 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Architecture Course of Study, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Architecture Planning Committee
    - General, 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence
      - 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 32)
      - 1952-1956 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Minutes and votes, 1950-1956 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Executive Committee, Department of Architecture, Minutes, 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Alumni, 1955-1966
    - Chicago Yale Festival Exhibition, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Alumni Newsletter, Yale's Departments of Art & Architecture, 1955-1961 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Alumni Magazine -C.L.V. Meeks, 1958, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Luncheon, American Institute of Architects (AIA) Convention, April 25, Philadelphia, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Meeting at Mory's, 1962 January 8 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - American Institute of Architects (AIA) Convention, May 7-9, Dallas, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Newsletter, Architecture, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Executive Committee, Dinner Meeting, & NY Meeting, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Miami Beach Convention, American Institute of Architects (AIA), 1963 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Executive Committee
      - 1963 November (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - 1965 October (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - 1966 April 15 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Alumni Board, 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Class Agents, letters
      - 1963-1965 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - Sample letters, 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Albany alumni meeting, June 2, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - LYBUNT Letter, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Newsletter, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Regional Yale Architecture Alumni (YAA) Groups, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Alumni Seminar, March 19-20, San Francisco, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Pittsburgh Alumni Regional Meeting, January 21-22, 1966, 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Alumni Fund
      - 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 24)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Alumni Magazine contributors, 1968-1969 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - President's Committee on Alumni Affairs, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Alumni correspondence (Yale Arts Association, EYE ), 1968-1969 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Gifts: Art and Architecture, 1968-1969 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - The New School Tie, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Alumni Gift Memos, Lenahan Memorial Lecture, 1994-1995 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Perspecta, 1954-1966
    - Correspondence
      - 1954 (Box 23, Folder 33)
      - Gift Memos, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 34)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 35)
      - Letters for Contribution, 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Finland - Michael Dobbins, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Minutes, 1955-1962 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Perspecta II -Craig Whitaker (Fellini letter), 1964 (Box 23, Folder 39)
- Student registration book, 1875-1922; Accession 2002-A-113
  - Student registration book, 1875-1922 (Box 1)
- Curriculum and faculty records, circa 1956-1967; Accession 2004-A-042
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2043
  No inventory available.
  - Programs, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Design problems (all classes), 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Thesis programs, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Thesis programs, fall, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Theses, department of Architecture and section of city planning, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Thesis programs, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Thesis programs (spring), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Second year design problems, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Second year design problems, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Second year design problems, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Second year design problems, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Second year design problems, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Second year design programs, file copies, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Second year architectural design, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Second year design, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Second year design, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Second year architectural design, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Second year design, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Second year design, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Third year design problems, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Third year design problems, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Third year design problems, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Third year design problems, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Third year design problems, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Third year design programs, file copies, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Third year architectural design, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Koppers luncheon, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Third year design problems, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Third year design, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Third year architectural design, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Third year design, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Third year design, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Fourth year design and thesis, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minimum requirements for 1961-1962 theses (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Fourth year design programs, file copies, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fourth year architectural design, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fourth year design, criticism schedule, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fourth year and thesis, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - B. Architecture thesis, fall term, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - B. Architecture thesis, spring term, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fourth year design, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Design problems, first year, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Design problems, first year, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Design problems, first year, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - design problems, first year, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Design problems, first year, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Design problems, first year, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Second year design problems, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Second year design problems, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Second year design problems, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Second year design problems, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Second year design problems, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Second year design problems, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Third year design problems, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Third year design problems, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Third year design problems, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Third year design problems, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Third year design problems, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Third year design, masters, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Fourth year design problems, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Master's class design problems, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Master's class design problems, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Master's class design problems, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Master's class design problems, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Master's class design problems, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Master's class design problems, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Master's class design, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Master's class design problems, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Master's class, design list, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Master's class design programs for 1960-1961, file copies (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Master's class design problem, study on precast conrete, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Master's class thesis programs, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Master's architectural design, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Master's design problems, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Master's class design, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Master's class design, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Master's class (parts I, II and III), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
  - Master's class spring term, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Davenport, Shirley, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Advanced studies, 1952-1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Gute, Herbert J., 1949-1952 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Meeks, Carroll Louis Vanderslice, September 1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Meeks, Carroll Louis Vanderslice correspondence (July 1957-June 1958), 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Meeks, Carroll Louis Vanderslice correspondence (September 1956- June 1957), 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Meeks, Carroll Louis Vanderslice, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Meeks, Carroll Louis Vanderslice (personal current correspondence), 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Nelson, Hazel May, 1955-1958 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Welliver, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Frost, Alfred; city planning, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Rado, L. L., 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Albers, Josef, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Sawyer, Charles Henry, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Meeks. Carroll Louis Valderslide (personal - prev. correspondence), 1947-1951 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Kahn, Louis I., 1949-1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Supplies, Arch. 11 and Arch. 13, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Stationary and envelopes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Scully, Vincent Joseph Jr., 1947-1957 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Faculty, past correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous materials, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Reports & letters on a "Center for the Arts at Yale", and the Hopper Fellowship, 1954-1958; Accession 2004-A-048
  - Reports & letters on a "Center for the Arts at Yale", and the Hopper Fellowship, 1954-1958 (Box 1)
- Records concerning the development of film and television production as a degree program, 1949-1969; Accession 2004-A-062
  - Films: correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Friends of Film, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Films: correspondence with Chester LaRoche, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Films: correspondence with George R. Hill, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Film: University Film Study Center, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Film proposals, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Films: Yale Film Council, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Films: correspondence with Stan Lawder, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Films: correspondence Walker Buckner, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Library Film Committee, 1949-1954 (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
  - Films: Thorne Films, Inc., 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Films: Yale Film Festival, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Audio Visual Center, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Films, Incorporated, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Job seekers, film, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Films, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Film catalogues, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Griggs Film Collection, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Television Film: alums Yale and out, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Television project, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Television: correspondence with Walker Buckner, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Television: correspondence with Walker Buckner, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Television program guides, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Television: Triangle Publications, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Television: correspondence, misc., 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Television: correspondence with Walker Buckner, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Television: National Education Television Network, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Television: National Association of Education Broadcasters (NAEB), 1969-1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Television: National Citizens for Public Television, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Television: WGBH, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Art Department, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - Art school, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Art Gallery building fund, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Art Association Alumni Fund, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Faculty and Division meeting minutes, reports, student lists, and photographs, circa 1921-1963; Accession 2006-A-188
  - Faculty meeting minutes (Volume V), 1932-1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Division and faculty meeting minutes, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Report on the Work of the Committee on Architectural Plan from its Establishment in 1911 until 1931 by John V. Farwell", undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Student Lists, 1921-1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Kopper's [Architectural Student Design Competition photographs], 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fourth Year photographs of students, circa 1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Filmpack #1 photographic negatives, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)